Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I'd
love to welcome you and call the order
to order our January 12th meeting of the
governing body. Madame clerk, would you
take the role, please?
>> Mayor Collins,
>> present.
>> Dr. Emmens,
>> Mr. Esabel,
>> here.
>> Mr. Lebornne,
>> Mr. Moody,
>> here.
>> Dr. Renie,
>> present.
>> Mr. Crave,
>> Mr. White,
>> present.
>> Mr. Wolf,
>> here.
>> Dr. Aldrich,
>> present. All members are present. We do
have a quorum. Would you all join me
please in the pledge of allegiance?
>> I pledge algiance to the flag of the
United States of America and to the
republic for it stands one nation
indivisible with liberty and justice for
all.
Consent agenda. All agenda items listed
with the designation of CA are
considered to be routine items by the
governing body and will be enacted by
one motion. There will be no separate
discussion on these items unless a
member of the governing body so requests
and support by two other members is
received. Any item removed from the
consent agenda will be considered in its
normal sequence on the agenda.
All right. Are there any items a member
of this governing body would like to
remove from the consent agenda? Mr.
Leborn.
>> Mr. Mayor. Number 22A.
>> Concur.
>> Okay. We'll remove 22A from the consent
agenda. Anyone else hearing? None. I
would entertain a motion.
>> So moved.
>> Second.
>> That was Mr. Escoel.
Second by Dr. Aldridge. All those in
favor of the consent agenda, please
signify by saying I. I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. The consent agenda is
approved with item 22A removed.
>> Number six, election of city council
president for 2026.
>> All right. Annually, the city council
elects their leaders for the uh the the
next year. Um while I don't get to vote
because I'm not a member of the city
council, I do uh run the meeting. And so
at this time I would open it up for
nominations for the office of city
council president for the year 2026.
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes sir. Mr. Escobel.
>> I nominate Councilman Tom Crave for
president.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. White.
Are there any other nominations?
If not, I would entertain a motion to
cease nominations.
>> I'd move to cease nominations.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Dr. Aldridge and seconded by
Mr. Wolf to cease nominations. All those
in favor of ceasing nominations, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. All right, we have a vote
for the president of our city council,
Mr. Tom Seager, has been nominated. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. Mr. Seager is unanimously
elected president. Congratulations, sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Number seven, election of city council
vice president.
[applause]
>> Next election then is for vice
president. same rules. I would entertain
a motion for the vice president of the
city council.
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> I move to uh nominate Pete Lebornne for
vice president of the council.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Moody. So, it's been
moved by Dr. Emmen, seconded by Mr.
Moody. Are there any other nominations?
I'd entertain a motion to cease
nominations.
>> So, move.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Dr. Aldridge and seconded
by Mr. White to cease nominations. All
those in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed. All right, we're on the
motion to elect Mr. Leborn, vice
president of the city council. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed? Mr. Labour is unanimously
elected vice president. Congratulations,
[applause] sir.
Number 8, a public hearing to determine
whether compliance of annexation
conditions required by Wyoming statute
15-1-402
exists for the city initiated annexation
of 26 parcels of land totaling roughly
279.98
acres comprised of various tracks of
land. Situit in North Cheyenne,
generally located south of Story
Boulevard, east of Powder House Road,
north of Del Range Boulevard, and west
of Ridge Road.
>> All right. Well, before we go out to the
public to uh get comments, we'll do a
quick staff report with Mr. White. Thank
you, sir.
>> Mayor, members of council, Conor White
Planning Development Department,
the sanctation is for 26 parcels of land
totaling roughly 279.98
acres, generally located south of Story
Boulevard, east of Powder House Road,
north of Del Range, and west of Ridge
Road. the city. Uh this is a city
initiated annexation uh present to
Wyoming state statute 15-1-404.
A resolution initiating this annexation
was adopted by the governing body on
December 22nd uh 2025.
This public hearing is being held in
accordance with Wyoming state statute
15-1-42A.
And then pursuant to fulfilling the
requirements of state statute, staff
asks the governing body to consider the
following. The land proposed to be
annexed is contiguous to city limits.
Specifically, uh the parcels are 100%
contiguous.
All city services and utilities
currently available to residents of the
city will be provided to the residents
of the annex land extending water and
sewer will increase the health, safety
and or health and safety of the
residents living in the area of the
community.
The area to be annexed is consider or is
inside the urban service boundary and
designated with mixeduse commercial and
urban residential by the future land use
map. This type of development is best
supported by being within city limits
and connecting to city services.
Certified uh mailing was sent to all
land owners and utilities within the
area uh the annexed area not less than
20 business days prior to the public
hearing tonight. According to the
calendar, 20 business days prior to
today's public hearing was December 9th,
uh, 2025, and certified mailing was sent
out on December 5th, and the earliest
confirmed receipt was on December 8th,
and property owners within 300 ft of
these areas uh were also mailed notice
at that same time. Um, this is
accompanied by an assigned zoning
ordinance as well. And I know I always
get the question um with this pocket
there are only four property owners um
for this basically the land to be
annexed. One being the Cole family of
Edwards Development, the city and
uh the school district. Cole family is
on board with the annexation which are
they're predominantly the ones with
section 20 and then the Edwards
properties on the east or yeah east side
of Converse. Um they're also in favor of
the annexation. So just haven't heard
from the school district or the city uh
for comments, but I'm assuming the
city's probably fine.
>> I think we're okay with it, sir. All
right, let's go out to the governing
body. Anybody have any question for
staff?
Connor, thank you. Stand by. Anybody in
the audience here today to speak to this
annexation? Uh this is a city council
goal that we we started in 2021
to annex properties 100% surrounded by
the city um to clean up some regulatory
issues that come with that and this is
the ninth iteration that we're almost
complete now after five years of working
on this project. Anybody in the
audience?
All right. Hearing none. The purpose of
the public hearing has been met. Next
item, please.
>> Number 8B. Public hearing for a transfer
of ownership of retail liquor license
application filed with the city clerk's
office for AC's range LLC doing business
as AC's range 1505 Pioneer Avenue
Cheyenne Wyoming license currently held
by FNG Corporation doing business as the
green door.
>> All right, before us we have a public
hearing. The uh green door is no more
and uh their liquor license is available
and AC's range has asked to uh have that
transferred to them. Is there anybody
here today that would like to speak to
that transfer of the retail liquor
license?
>> Do me a favor and push that button and
turn on that microphone. There you go.
Thank you.
>> Got it. Mr. Mayor, I'm Ben Troutwine,
FNG Corporation,
and um I'm here to uh answer any
questions there might be, but I most of
all I just wanted to say I fully support
the sale. I think it's going to be a
great use for the liquor license and I
think the new ownership will do a great
job.
>> Thank you, Ben. Appreciate you being
here tonight.
>> Good evening, Mr. Mayor and city
council. My name is JB Coons and I am
the operating owner manager of Aces
Range and I am here before you to answer
any questions you may have for me in our
acquisition of this liquor license.
>> Very good. Does anybody in the governing
body have a question for the applicant?
>> I do.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Uh thank you, Mayor Thu. I'm just um
wondering if uh can you tell us a little
bit about how you'll fully fully utilize
this license that is for retail liquor
license?
>> Yes, ma'am. Mr. mayor through you to Dr.
Aldridge. Uh we have the ability to take
the Trackmans anywhere. Uh we can set up
a an experience where we bring uh the
Trackmans to a location. Uh so I believe
that would satisfy that requirement. Uh
in so far as a liquor retail store, uh
we do have an area that we can designate
in the on our premise that can serve as
a store. But furthermore, the idea is to
uh be more of an order service for
people. Uh if they would like a fine
bottle of wine or scotch, whiskey,
whatever they would like, uh we can get
that ordered for them. Uh and be a
liquor store in that sense of a word. Uh
do
>> you have any other questions for me or
does that answer
>> Dr. Albert? Any followup? I had one
follow-up question which is uh for our
um city clerk and that's that um my
understanding of state statute is that
uh those who hold a liquor license can
only hold one. So will that result in a
tavern license coming back to uh the
city to be relet?
>> I think it's a bar and grill.
>> Bar and grill.
>> Yes, Mr. Mayor through you to Dr.
Aldrich. believe the um idea is for the
um business aces range to relinquish
their bar and grill at the time of the
approval of the retailer license.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh
>> that's your understanding also J?
>> Yes, that is my intention and
understanding that we will relinquish
our bar and grill license in lie of uh
procuring this liquor license, full
retail license.
>> If you wanted to double pay for
licenser, we're never going to argue
with that, but I think that's good
business. I think it would help the city
to have another bar and grill available
to entrepreneurs.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Mr. Mayor, thank you uh through you. Um
Mr. Coun, um pardon my ignorance, but
what is it that you do? What what is
your and and before you answer that, let
me just make one very personal comment
is that um I knew your father very very
well and had tremendous regard for him.
Uh he's a very fine man. So,
Uh, Mr. Mayor, to you, Councilman Wolf.
I appreciate that very much. He was a
devout Wyomingite uh, and was very, uh,
interested in the policy that, uh,
shapes the state. Uh, we at Aces Range
are a golf simulator business. We also
just acquired a recent, uh, acquisition
that is another sim. It's a a full-on
racing sim that uh provides four degrees
of freedom as they call it, but in the
layman terms, you can um do a full donut
in it and actually spin around in this
contraption that we have put in Aces
Range. Uh we are a new concept of an
entertainment venue that isn't
necessarily a restaurant. It isn't
necessarily bar and grill. Uh we provide
uh a great uh location for private
parties, things like that, as well as
hosting golf leagues. We have six
Trackman, golf bays, uh racing bay, and
then a shooting bay and a
open area where we host uh quite a few
team building parties and holiday
parties for companies in Cheyenne.
>> Followup, Mr. Wolf.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> Okay,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Mr. Escoel. um for my colleagues
edification. So, uh simulating golf, can
you let us know how many different golf
courses you can actually play in those
simulators?
>> Uh I believe the last count was 350
something. Uh or excuse me, sorry, Mr.
Mayor threw you to Councilman Esel. Uh I
believe it's 300 and something. It's
always a
continuing uh
aspect of Trackman's business where they
send these drones to golf courses and
then render them into uh software uh
that we then utilize. We're constantly
uploading and downloading courses. Our
computers memories are completely full
of uh courses and activities that are uh
related to and used by the Trackman app.
Thank you.
>> So, Mr. Mayor, I think we got about 299
more courses to go.
>> I think we do,
>> Mr. Coons. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Good luck to you, sir.
>> Appreciate it. Thank you, sir.
>> Miss Coons, welcome.
It's been a while since we've had you
here. Thank you.
>> Yes.
Thank you very much. Thank you, Mr.
Mayor and City Council members. I'm
April Bremer Coons, 6210 Bremer Road,
Cheyenne, Wyoming.
I am the financial part of AC's range.
And what my son didn't tell you, Mr.
Mayor and council, is that this racing
sim
duplicates NASCAR and Formula 1.
>> And when he very politely said, "Mom, do
you want to try it?" I politely said,
"No, thank you." [laughter]
So I stand for questions. This would
help us immensely, Mr. Mayor and council
members, to have a full liquor license.
We are restricted with the legislation
that we worked so hard to pass, Mr.
Mayor
uh to 40% alcohol.
And it becomes a real issue for AC's
range financially
because we sometimes can't have the
parties we'd like to have because we
don't want to violate the 40%.
Our record is clean. I think we have
shown that we know how to manage a
liquor license and would hope sincerely
that you would consider this transfer.
It is a private transfer.
um very honored and I'm grateful that my
parents haven't sent a bolt of lightning
that it's from the green door.
[laughter]
>> I stand for questions, Mr. Mayor.
>> We're happy to have you here tonight.
Thank you. Anybody have any questions
for the applicant?
>> I just have a comment. Mayor,
>> thank you.
>> Mayor Collins through you. Um I've had
the opportunity to attend four or five
events. um team building and party,
Christmas party, those types of things
at your venue. And um really I think for
people in our audience tonight, really
what JB really downplayed was that there
is a shooting range simulation that
actually is uh really uh there is a huge
variety of shooting as well as golf. So
um for those that might be of that
persuasion, um there's something there
for everybody. So we wish you the best
of luck.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, ma'am. appreciate you being
here tonight. Let's open it up to the
public. Is anybody here to speak to the
uh transfer of this liquor license?
>> Anybody in the public?
>> All right. Anybody on the governing
body?
>> All right. The purpose of the public
hearing has been met and we'll assign
this item also to the public service or
the finance committee.
>> Number 8 C. Public hearing for a
transfer of ownership of retail liquor
license application filed with the city
clerk's office for Westby Edge LLC doing
business as Westby Edge Brewing 714 West
20th Street Cheyenne Wyoming license
currently held by Scooters Scoreboard
Bar Inc.
>> All right, we'll open it up to the
public again and one thing I maybe I
could just do. We have a lot of new
people in the audience today and we're
excited that you're all here. um when uh
a liquor license is uh not being used,
we call that going into a park status.
And state law allows you to park it for
one year and then if they come back to
the governing body, they can park it for
a second year. If they don't reuse that
license, then they relinquish it. It
comes back to the city council. And so,
um we're we've had a couple liquor
licenses that have been parked for a
while and they're now coming, uh to the
end of that time frame. And so that's
why we're seeing these uh this this
activity going on this evening for these
liquor licenses. I think the one that
we're going to talk about now, I think
it's the 23rd of January, if it's not
transferred by then, uh then the owner
of that liquor license loses it and the
value that goes with it. So go ahead,
Mr. Westby.
>> Good evening.
>> Good evening. Terry Cassidy, 2814 Kerry
Avenue. Um, I'm here on behalf of the
scooters folks who will be transferring
this license hopefully um over to
Westb's Edge. Um, the owners of Westb
are also here tonight to speak to the
license, but I am obviously in in
support of it. Fantastic ownership. Um,
a really good track record and I think
that they'll do some really nice things
with it. Any questions for me? No.
>> Thank you very much. Anybody?
Thanks, Miss Cassidy. Mr. Westby,
welcome. Bring that microphone up, would
you, sir?
>> Good evening.
>> Uh, Mr. Mayor, Council, uh, Darren
Westby, 714 West 20th, West Bedge
Brewing. Uh, we're just really proud to
be a part of something very significant
that's been happening downtown with the
revitalization, especially on the west
edge um that we're a part of. Uh, really
proud of everything that's going on. we
bringing thousands of people um to
downtown that we hadn't seen in quite a
while. Uh it was kind of interesting the
night before Thanksgiving. Uh
we had a big crowd at our place, but my
wife and I decided we'd take a little
walk just to see how the rest of
downtown's doing. uh went over to uh our
our friends about a block and a half to
the to the east of us and they were
packed and we just had a moment to
reflect a little bit about five years
ago, the night before Thanksgiving or
any night in downtown at least on that
edge of downtown would have been vacant
and now we have thousands of people down
there and so really proud to be a part
of that. um really proud to have the
opportunity to um hopefully get the
transfer of the liquor license to help
expand upon about what we have to offer
uh to the downtown with that regard. And
so uh gratefully worked with the
Winklers on the on the sale and
hopefully the transfer and I would stand
for any questions.
>> Mr. Westby, can you uh I know the
question is going to come share how
you're going to use the license, please.
>> Sure. uh very similar to um what AC's
range is doing. It it gives us a little
bit more flexibility with the 60/40
split. Um operationally, if I would just
tell you right now from 9:00 till 11:00
on a Friday or Saturday, we sell maybe
one pizza. Uh having that flexibility to
not have to be open every hour that
we're open with the with the other
business there would give us that
flexibility. Um, one, we're killing our
cook and I don't want to do that. She's
awesome and amazing. Um, so the liquor
store, uh, you know, something that we
wanted from the beginning when we
started developing, uh, Westb Edge was
to carve out a piece of that to give an
opportunity for package uh, retail as
well. And so we're kind of coming full
circle uh with this potential uh to be
able to offer on this west edge another
opportunity with that. Uh as you noticed
a big structure being built just to the
west of here. Um yeah, west of here uh
south of here. Um the big apartment
complex going up. It's going to be
transformational uh for the downtown,
not just the west edge, the entire
downtown. And we're proud to be a part
of that in a way that we also come in
full circle with the business plan that
started six years ago of you know what
if you know there's a desert here of
grocery as well. So we're looking to
possibly carve that out that has nothing
to do with the liquor license but that
same space we're looking to provide
another amenity for the people in the
west edge of downtown and downtown in
general. So uh our daughter also to try
to carve off the all three points of of
this license. Our daughter owns a event
planning business. Uh she does weddings.
She does she does parties. This would
also allow us to be able to take this
liquor license and uh help the community
have events outside of our location and
other locations. And so yes, that's the
kind of the trifecta that we like to see
happen, kind of coming full circle with
the original business plan. Any
questions from the council on the uh
applicant?
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins for you. I'm wondering if
you have any plans for are you thinking
um of a drive-thru um package liquor or
are you thinking it's going to be simply
uh set up where they would have to come
in and go into retail?
>> Mr. Westby,
>> Mr. Mayor, Councilman, um
we really don't have the ability with
our property lines and with our existing
facilities around us to have a drive up.
Uh so we were looking at possibly a
curbside um with all the legal amenities
that have to happen with that uh just to
add some convenience, but that's
something that we're talking about, but
drive up is not a a option right now.
>> Anyone else?
Thank you, M. Westpine. Good luck.
>> Thank you.
>> Anybody else in the audience here today
that would like to speak to this
transfer of a retail liquor license?
>> No one. All right. The purpose of this
public hearing has been met and will
also assign this item to the finance
committee. Number nine, ordinance, third
reading, defining the terms and
conditions of employment for sworn
officers of the Cheyenne Police
Department for January 2026 until the
end of fiscal year 2026. All right, this
is our annual review of the terms and
conditions for our police department.
And I think there's two major changes.
Um, a 3% cost of living allowance that
was given to our employees and then a
change in a little bit in the longevity
pay police officers might be able to
earn as they uh go through their career.
We'll open up to the public. Is there
anybody in the public that would like to
speak to this ordinance on third and
final reading?
>> All right, I hear none. Mr. Leborn, are
you ready?
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to approve on third
and final reading and I so move.
>> Second and seconded by Mr. Moody.
Comments from members of the governing
body.
>> Hearing none. Madam clerk, would you
take the vote?
>> Dr. Aldrich?
>> Yes.
>> Mayor Collins?
>> Dr. Emmens?
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Escoel?
>> I.
>> Mr. Leborn.
>> Hi.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Dr. Renie,
Yes,
>> Mr. Crave.
>> Yes,
>> Mr. White.
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> I.
>> This ordinance is approved on third and
final reading. [clears throat]
>> Number 10, ordinance, second reading,
creating chapter 1.28, administrative
inspection warrants, establishing
authority for their issuance, and
amending the municipal code of the city
of Cheyenne, Wyoming, to authorize
certain city officials as specified to
apply for administrative inspection
warrants.
>> All right. This ordinance would create a
process for our fire chief and chief
building official to receive an
administrative warrant. Um, I see a lot
of new faces here today, so I thought
maybe if you don't mind, I just go
through how we do this. All right. So,
we have two microphones, one on each
side. You're welcome to uh come up to
either one of those microphones. We ask
that you identify yourself clearly for
the record. Um, and then bring that
microphone so it's right up in front of
you because if you're over like this,
people can't hear you very well. So,
just make sure that microphone's just a
couple inches away from your face. And
then we give each person three minutes.
So, we'd love to have you come up and
and share with you your thoughts on this
ordinance on second reading. And uh
someone needs to start us off.
>> Mr. Brown, before you get started, I owe
you an apology, sir.
>> Last time you were here, we were talking
about affordable housing and uh um
well, you know, we invite people to come
and speak to us, and maybe we could have
been a I could have been a little bit
more polite to you. So, I've been
waiting for you the chance to come back
so I could make that apology in person,
but uh appreciate you coming back this
evening. Looking forward to your
comments, sir.
>> Appreciate it, Mr. Mayor. Thank you. And
uh thank you, Mr. Mayor. City Council,
Exie Brown, Ward 2. I'm here to
respectfully ask that you reject this
ordinance. This does violate the Fourth
Amendment of the US Constitution and
Article One, Section 4 of the Wyoming
State Constitution. And we can twist
words. We can use words like inspection
versus search. We can twist the law. We
can twist these things up. But at the
end of the day, the overarching of this
ordinance does violate the fourth
amendment and article 1 section 4 and is
textbook government overreach giving
more power to our unelected bureaucrats.
Now, I know there's going to be case law
thrown out there about Kamara versus San
Francisco and C's versus Seattle and how
the Supreme Court ruled in those.
However, just last week, Pennsylvania
Commonwealth Court ruled in Riviera vers
the burrow of Pottstown in a unanimous
inbach opinion to decline to follow the
US Supreme Court ruling in these and I
quote so-called administrative warrants
without suspicion of wrongdoing. Now,
while this ordinance may have some good
intentions, good intentions do not make
good policy.
The media reported uh that Councilman
Seagra made the comment that there was
only going to be probably about 10 of
these used a year. Well, those need to
be utilized individually and separate.
We don't have to do a blanket coverage
for an entire ordinance for entire city.
That puts 61,000 people at risk of
having their Fourth Amendment violated.
Fire Chief even made comments during the
committee meeting that most people
consent. They typically don't have a
problem with people consenting to them
coming in. And that's how it's supposed
to be to have consent. The Fourth
Amendment was set up to where it's
supposed to be hard for government and
unelected bureaucrats to come on to your
private property. Cuz really, how where
does it stop? Do we just start off with
abandoned buildings? Next thing you
know, we have what rent control to where
property owners cannot make enough money
to maintain maintenance on these
facilities. We come in and do an
inspection and now we're condemning
properties. city buys the properties
from the property owners and we start
building more of the affordable housing
scams. I mean, where does it begin? Do
we have selective enforcement under the
guise of safety? What happens to council
members or on councils 5, 10, 15, 20
years down the road and the unelected
bureaucrats that far down the road? How
are they going to utilize this ordinance
and in what way? This policy is stuff
you see in San Francisco, Seattle,
Boulder, Fort Collins, and with that new
communist socialist mayor out in New
York. We are not that. We need to stop
chipping away at the constitutional
rights as these ordinances kind of do,
and we need to stop trying to Colorado
or California or Wyoming. Again, thank
you all for your time, and I appreciate
it.
>> Thank you, sir.
Not let's not do that. Okay, let's not
do that. We're not gonna [clears throat]
We're going to listen politely. Thank
you.
>> Good evening, Mayor Collins, members of
the council. My name is Gary Pew.
>> My wife and I have lived in Cheyenne for
five years.
>> Welcome.
>> I spent over 20 years in the United
States Air Force, retiring as a master
sergeant in charge of avionics of a
fighter group. My first day in uniform,
I raised my right hand and swore an oath
to support, excuse me, to support and
defend the Constitution of the United
States. I took that oath seriously
then, and I take that oath seriously
now. That's why I'm here tonight,
because Chapter 1.28 asks you to create
a warrant that isn't a really a warrant
at all. Our Wyoming Constitution,
Article 1, Section 4, requires that
warrants issue only upon, and I quote,
probable cause supported by affidavit.
End quote. Let me say that again. Our
Wyoming Constitution, Article 1, Section
4, requires that warrants issue only
upon probable cause, supported by
affidavit. That language isn't an
accident. Our founders, state and
federal, understood that when government
can enter your home simply because it
wants to check on you, you don't really
own that home. You are just borrowing
it.
This ordinance allows warrants to be
issued merely to determine, discover, or
verify compliance. I want you to think
about what that standard actually means.
Every inspection exists to determine,
discover, and verify compliance. That's
the purpose of inspections.
When the standard for getting a warrant
is simply wanting to conduct an
inspection,
the purpose of the inspe when the
standard for getting a warrant is simply
wanting to conduct an inspection. What
grounds would a judge ever have to say
no?
The answer is none.
When a judge can't say no, you do not
have judicial oversight. You have a
rubber stamp.
I've heard it said that this is settled
law that the courts have blessed
administrative warrants. That may be
true under federal law, but Wyoming's
constitution uses different language and
stronger language than the fourth
amendment. Article 1 section 4 has
repeatedly held that our state
constitution provides greater protection
than its federal counterpart.
In the case cited by council members on
social media, Hill versus City of
Laramie is about building permits and
civil procedure. It says nothing about
administrative warrants, nothing about
the Fourth Amendment and nothing that
authorizes what you're being asked to
approve tonight.
I would encourage everyone citing legal
authority to make sure they've actually
read it.
I've also heard that this is only for
abandoned properties, but I've read the
ordinance
and that limitation appears nowhere in
the text.
Verbal assurances don't bind future
councils or future code enforcement
officers.
This once this tool exists, it will
expand.
That's not speculation. That's how
government works.
>> Mr. Pew, your time is up.
>> I'm okay. Thank you very much.
>> Appreciate you being here, sir. Thank
Thank you. Welcome again to Cheyenne.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Hello, mayor and members of the city
council. My name is Kathy Sigleaniano
and I am a resident here in Cheyenne. I
strongly oppose this ordinance
authorizing administrative inspection
warrants. You each took an oath, an oath
to uphold the United States and Wyoming
Constitutions. That oath matters. This
ordinance violates it. Calling these
warrants noncriminal does not change
what they are. Government permission to
enter private property without consent
and in some cases without notice. This
is exactly what our Fourth Amendment was
written to prevent. If there is no
active emergency, the government has no
business forcing its way onto private
property. Language in this ordinance is
vague and dangerously broad. Phrase.
Phrases like permission unobtainable or
allowing notice to be skipped if it
might interfere with an inspection give
unelected officials far too much
discretion.
That is not a safeguard. It's a
violation to abuse.
Private property rights do not disappear
because access is inconvenient or an
owner says no. Emergencies are already
covered under existing law. This
ordinance is unnecessary, excessive, and
sets dangerous precedent. Once
government power is expanded, it is
rarely rolled back. Every resident
should be concerned about where this
leads. I urge you to reject this
ordinance and uphold the constitutional
rights you swore to protect. Thank you.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, I'm gonna just
take just a second here. Um
my handy pocket United States
Constitution Article 4 is one sentence.
The right of the people to be secure in
their persons, houses, papers, and
effects shall unstreasonable
searches and seizures shall not be
violated, and no warrant shall be
issued. but upon probable cause
supported by an oath or affirmation and
particularly describing the place to be
searched and the persons or things to be
seized. That's United States
Constitution. The Wyoming Constitution
is exactly the same word for word.
Section four, I don't have to read it
again. It is the exact same wordage. So,
it's not stronger. It is literally the
exact same words.
>> Yes, ma'am.
Push it till the green button. There you
go. Thank you.
>> I'm Katie Bradfield.
>> Welcome.
>> Word three. I'm super nervous. So,
>> don't be nervous. Just tell us what
you're thinking.
>> Um, thanks. Um, I just am here tonight
again and I originally emailed all of
you guys last week about this and I
appreciate the responses. Um, and I
didn't want to be just a keyboard
warrior, so I actually wanted to show up
in person. Um, and I just wanted to ask
that you vote against this. Um, and if
you do see that you want to go through
with this, I just ask that you look
further into it and possibly look at
rewarding it, really expanding on if
it's going to be just for the abandoned
and vacant properties like so many
people online are saying that it is for,
um, and really put limits to it. Um, in
one of the articles that I read online,
someone was stating that, you know, they
might go into a house and people don't
want them to look in certain areas of
their house. And to me, I can agree with
that. If I have a renovation and I'm
having my home um, like a bathroom
remodel and I'm having an inspector come
check to see if it's proper, I don't
feel like they need to go to the
basement. And I mean, it's a mess all
the time. So to me, you should only go
in the area that needs to be looked at.
Um, so but overall, I guess I just ask
that you vote no on it unless you really
work on the wording and restrictions in
it. Thank you.
>> There was no reason to be nervous, was
there?
>> My leg is shaking. [laughter]
>> Thanks for being here tonight, sir.
Welcome.
>> Mayor, [clears throat] excuse me, Mayor
Collins and city council members. Thank
you for giving me the opportunity to
speak to you regarding ordinance 1.28.
My name is John Frank. I reside at 6916
Snowy River Road here in Cheyenne. I've
lived here for six and a half years.
Wyoming is my adopted home state after
living through the damage done to
Colorado
>> and uh it's and Colorado is the state in
which I was born.
I emailed the message to all members of
the city council this morning and will
not reread that message. You should all
have a copy of that. The situation cited
as the need for this ordinance from my
read of the city code and the Wyoming
statutes are already addressed in law.
Since these violations are already
addressed, makes me wonder as to the
real motivation behind this u this
proposed ordinance.
respect for private property undergurs
so much of what excuse me of what makes
America the great country uh that
America is
and sets the US apart from almost every
other country especially every socialist
country.
I am uh restating formally and
unequivocally my opposition to this
proposed ordinance to authorized
administrative inspection warrant and
urge you to vote against proposed
ordinance 1.28.
Thank you for your time.
>> Thank you, sir. Appreciate you being
here this evening.
>> Sir,
>> hello Mr. Mayor.
>> Looks like we have something.
>> Yeah, we got brothers.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> welcome. Thank you and thank you for the
time. I'm going to be short and sweet.
I've read the ordinance as proposed.
>> Will you introduce yourself, please?
>> Oh, I'm sorry. I'm Dee Rearden. Uh I've
been in Cheyenne about five years as
well.
>> Welcome, sir.
>> Um I've read the ordinance or proposed
ordinance and I've watched the public
service committee uh meeting from
January 5th and I don't I don't disagree
that the city needs to do something with
the abandoned buildings. They're all
over the place. It doesn't matter which
part of town you go to, you can find an
abandoned building, um, house, whatever
it is, and they look horrible. And some
of them are, um, public safety concerns,
and I think there needs to be something
done about that. I think there needs to
be an ordinance or whatever it is that
can be written to take care of that.
However, as the ordinance is written
right now, it doesn't um, doesn't even
mention abandoned buildings in it, much
less
the things that it could cover. And
that's what concerns me. I've heard it
from several people today about it could
cover anybody living in anything uh at
any point in time. And I don't think
that's the intent of the ordinance. I
think the intent of the ordinance is to
address and it should be to address Ben
buildings. So, I oppose the ordinance as
written, but I don't oppose taking
another look at it and going back and
rewriting it and being more specific to
what the city council is trying to
accomplish here. U, thank you for your
time. Appreciate it.
>> Thanks for coming this evening.
>> Welcome.
>> Mr. Mayor, point of order. If you would,
I I'd ask you to uh please tell the
audience that we're on second reading,
which means this will in fact go back to
a committee for further discussion of
it. So, tonight is not the last
decision.
Thank you.
I don't know if you guys are are not
unfamiliar with our our processes, this
is an ordinance and so we read it into
the record, then it goes to a committee,
then it comes here tonight on second
reading, goes back to the committee, and
then comes back two weeks from tonight
for the final decision. So there's lots
of opportunities between now and then
for amendments or uh or further work to
be done on an ordinance.
>> Ma'am,
>> Councilman Moody had his hand.
>> Just a point of information, uh Mr. Mr.
Mayor and everybody just remember it
does fail on second reading. It does
fail. Is that correct?
>> I believe that's correct.
>> Yes, ma'am. Welcome.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor, members of the
council. My name is Patricia McCoy. I've
been a resident of Cheyenne for the last
18 years and I'm here to voice my strong
opposition. While I appreciate Mr. Wolf
pointing out that this is indeed the
second reading and it will go back to
the committee should it pass. Our hopes
is that it would not pass and if it does
pass that you would send it back to the
committee with appropriate
recommendations for limitations. Um as
we debate the merits of this ordinance
we should reflect on the warning from
Benjamin Franklin. Those who would give
up essential liberty to purchase a
little temporary safety deserve neither
liberty nor safety. While this ordinance
is presented under the guise of safety,
we must ask at what cost? By creating a
path for administrative inspection
warrants, this council is asking us to
surrender the essential liberty of the
home for the temporary safety of an
administrative checklist. I want to
remind this council that Wyoming has a
proud and independent legal tradition of
protecting that liberty. In cases like
Oboy, O Boy versus State and Vasquez
versus State as recently as 1999, the
Wyoming Supreme Court has ruled that our
state constitution, Article 1, Section
4, which thank you again, Patrick
Collins, for pulling that up and reading
it for us, um, is actually greater
protection and individual privacy per
Wyoming Supreme Court than the Fourth
Amendment. Our our courts have rejected
the idea that the government can engage
in searches without specific indivi
individualized justification.
This ordinance bypasses that tradition.
It treats our private homes of Cheyenne
residents as government regulated
spaces. If the council is determined to
move forward, which it seems that it is,
this ordinance must be specifically
amended to prevent overreach. We have
seen quotes in the paper by Councilman
Laybourne saying that this is not
government overreach. This is for safety
and neighborhood cleanup. That sounds
fabulous and wonderful. No one wants to
see an abandoned building sitting empty
for years on end. However, we still have
our rights and we don't want to give
them to you.
I am proposing a strict limitation.
amend this ordinance to apply strictly
and exclusively to abandoned or
unoccupied structures where document
safety emergency already exists. Without
this narrow focus, we are left with a
slippery slope where any occupied home
could be subject to a court-ordered
entry for routine code enforcement. We
should not be giving the government a
skeleton key to our private residences.
And as Franklin warned, if we trade our
core liberties for this kind of
administrative safety, we will
eventually find that we have lost both.
I urge you to listen to the president of
our state courts and vote no on chapter
1.28. Let's keep the government out of
the living rooms of law-abiding
citizens. Thank
>> you for being here this evening, sir.
Welcome.
>> Thank you.
>> Honorable Mayor Collins and uh council
staff got your day. My name is Steve
Olsen. I've been a resident of Cheyenne,
Wyoming for 14 years.
One of my primary concerns about this
particular ordinance is uh the fact that
there are certain individuals where they
have abandoned vehicles and things and
we have a wonderful lovely town with a
group of people here who are very
tight-knit and one of the biggest issues
that I have is is that I have
encountered a a single mother uh two
children and she has a vehicle for
example who that that's not been
abandoned. she's been paying her uh
registration fees and things like that,
but this is one of the primary examples
of code enforcement that would if this
were to be passed that a code
enforcement officer could go right onto
her property and issue an abatement and
then how is she able to afford the
additional taxes and other additional
leans that may be placed on the
property? uh if a landlord, for example,
wasn't able to meet certain criteria
based on that code enforcement and these
legislations were passed, how would our
our citizens be able to afford this
additional 50% increase uh based on the
findings that they have. Another primary
concern that I have is is that I don't
know if these these things have already
been issued, but there have already been
several citizens who've already had code
enforcement placed on them already
without having any form of call or
search or seizure. So, this has been
kind of a primary concern of mine as a
citizen. So, I would strongly recommend
that this either be repealed or removed
entirely. Thank you.
>> Good evening, sir. How are you tonight?
I'm doing good, mayor. How you doing?
>> Good. Bring that. There you go.
>> Uh, my name is Clarence Fischer and uh,
I live here in Miami since 79 when I got
out of the military. I've been here on
and off. I become a permanent resident
since 2020. I own a business and I own a
ranchet. Uh, and uh, I wanted to come
here and I thank you, Councilman Wolf,
for stating what you stated. I wanted to
come here to voice my opinion at this
time. I live in the county and this is a
city ordinance for now. It could advance
to the county. I want to ask some
questions. I don't have enough time. So,
if we could get a yes and no answer for
one of y'all each question, I'll be
done. Um, this ordinance mostly is for
business
people who own uh business properties
and buildings. Am I not right?
No,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Sir,
>> no, you're not correct.
>> Okay. It's for residents also. Okay. And
does this cover dilapidated buildings of
re residents or just any resident?
>> Depends on the circumstances.
>> Depends on circumstances. Okay, that's
what I needed to know, sir. Um I uh am
opposed to this on that grounds because
if any ordinary citizen is given a a
warrant administrative warrant to enter
into anybody's property uh at any wheel
of a council member or whoever uh
because uh uh they believe that
something's going on in that residence
or if they enter in that residence under
the guise of inspection to make sure
it's uh properly taken care of or
whatever and then they see something
else or or they don't like something
else is going on in that resident or or
they don't like that person. Then uh
they say, "Oh, well, this property is
okay." But privately they go and discuss
something with the police or with
somebody else. Oh, we need to issue a
warrant for this or that because they're
doing this and that in their property.
That's where this uh rule breaks down
and is damaging to the citizen because
we're entering in under the guise of one
thing but it becomes something else uh
once they're in there. So we need to uh
rewrite this once you visit it, vote on
it, come back to vote on it. We need to
revisit this and decide against it
unless it's rewarded
so that the citizens don't suffer
uh this proposed ordinance.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Thank you, Mayor.
>> Welcome, ma'am.
>> Good evening, Mr. Mayor and Council. My
name is Aaron Edwards. I'm a member of
Ward One. Um I'm here to ask some
questions. maybe rhetorical, maybe not,
but some stuff for the council to
consider. Um, first one is how many
instances of entry denial have occurred
versus the number of times request has
been made. If you're talking one out of
every thousand, it's probably not
warranted. But if you're talking maybe
10 out of 10 requests are denied and
there's an issue, maybe there's
consideration for a conversation at that
point. But it'd really be interesting to
find that out. Some other issues are
with this statute or this ordinance are
some vagueness which I know other people
have brought up but there's mentioned
multiple times in here reasonleness. So
reasonable times reasonable manner what
is reasonable? It's not defined and I
think that that causes some vagueness
that can cause some problems in the
future. uh if if you're talking
reasonable times with city uh the daily
Monday through Friday time frames 9 to5
8 to5 most people are at work and if
you're knocking on their doors while
they're at work that's not a good faith
effort to try to make contact with them
so what is that reasonable time what is
that reasonable manner when you're
serving those warrants that's the same
question that applies if you're serving
them if they're at work how are they
going to be there to advocate for
themselves and additionally if they're
not there because they're busy working
are you going to bust down on the door
and just kind of break into the house.
How does that work? You know, you
haven't really defined any of that.
Furthermore, uh it doesn't include how
the basis upon which the cause exists is
obtained. I think that that is important
to include if you're going to move
forward with this. Um you need to
support your probable cause. You need to
support your reasons for being there.
Um, additionally in section C on page
two, it says that the standards for
conducting a routine, periodic or area
inspection, so what does routine mean?
Are we talking regular inspections just
because you want to go in and see
somebody's house or is this because
there is an issue? So, I think that
there needs to be clarification on that.
Um, and additionally with that in the
same section, it says it's reasonably
necessary to determine, discover, or
verify the condition of the property.
While the words discover and determine
imply that you don't have any proof of
issues, it implies that there's a
fishing expedition to try to find reason
to gain entry to the property. That's at
least what it appears to me. Um, I can
tell you that in my professional life, I
deal with governmental liability and
traditionally in Wyoming, the courts are
not in favor of governmental entities
when there is vague language, whether
it's statutes or local ordinances. And
so I think that the vagueness here is a
big issue and it probably needs to be
cleaned up at that point. You might have
more support for it from the community.
I'm not sure. I don't want to speak on
behalf of them, but I I can tell you
that the vagueness is a is a big issue
and that could come come forward and and
cause some problems and it it does cause
some problems for me as a citizen. You
know, I like to live in my home free and
safe and know that my city council is
watching over everything. Thank you.
>> Thanks for being here this evening.
Good evening.
>> Good evening, Mayor Collins and city
council members. My name is Steve
Millia. I'm a
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor,
>> sir.
>> Would you please ask the witness to
remove his hat?
>> Government overreach.
>> Thank you, Steve.
>> Anyway, uh Mayor Collins and uh city
council members, thank you for this
opportunity. To be succinct, uh everyone
that has been before me has opposed
this. They have mentioned uh several
different uh ordinances and uh our court
cases etc. And Mary Collins, you had uh
read from the uh
>> constitution
>> constitution and we do want to be secure
in our homes and the idea of government
to an extent is to grow and grow and
grow and we do want to have our city
council watch out for us which we
appreciate that and I would stand in
opposition to this. Uh Miss McCoy and
Mr. Brown had brought up some very
excellent points. the previous lady also
brought up some very excellent points.
So, not to go over all of those, I'd
like to reiterate everything that you've
said. I haven't seen anything that I
disagreed with. I do think that if it
was rewritten
uh specifically only for abandoned
properties that have been there for what
a year, etc., then uh that would be good
as opposed to just u any old small
amount of time. So, I thank you for the
opportunity to speak and uh have a good
evening.
>> Thank you for being here. Don't forget
your hat,
>> sir.
>> My name is My name is Colin Crossman,
your honor. Members of council, uh I was
not going to speak tonight. Um however,
I will stress that I'm speaking in my
personal capacity and not in my official
capacity with uh with respect to my
employer. Uh, I did want to correct
something that I heard earlier and thank
you uh, mayor for reading the
>> mayor. Who is your employer?
>> I am the deputy secretary of state.
>> You're the deputy secretary of state.
Okay.
>> Um,
but I'm here in my personal capacity.
Um,
>> do you live in?
>> Yes, I do. I live in Ward One.
So, I'm your constituent, sir. Um,
you read from the US Constitution
earlier and you also mentioned that the
Wyoming Constitution was word for word
identical. That is incorrect. The actual
phrase is supported by affidavit whereas
the US Constitution says supported by
oath or affirmation.
>> You're right.
>> The U the Wyoming Supreme Court has held
that that slight change has means the
Wyoming Constitution is significantly
stronger. that goes back to Hall versus
State in 1996 as well as uh let me
Fulsson v state in 2017. So this is a
long-standing uh principle under Wyoming
law. That's the only comment I wish to
make.
>> Thanks for the correction. I appreciate
it. I just glanced at it real quickly
and I thought it was word for word, but
appreciate that, sir.
>> Good evening, uh Mayor Collins and
distinguished council. Thank you for the
opportunity to speak. Um, I'm John
Thomas. I live uh at the intersection
there of Day and Persing. So, Ward One.
Um, [clears throat]
I I appreciate all the legal language
that everybody's bringing up and the
vagueness in the bill or in the
ordinance. Uh, and that that's all very
important and that's that really is your
job to hammer that out to make sure that
the law works. That's not what I'm
talking about. I stand in opposition to
this bill because it violates the spirit
of the fourth amendment of the
Constitution of the United States. My
home is my castle. That comes from
what6003 in Great Britain. They had a
case, Seaman's case.
It's an old law. It's an ancient law.
It's it's it is critical that the
government, our elected governments,
protect our rights and not look for ways
to work around those rights. I have
never had a problem with the good
[clears throat] people um who enforce
building codes. I've had them come to my
house and look at work and found certain
items wanting that had to be corrected.
And for that I am grateful and I have
and I do not believe that they are uh
evil people with foul intent coming to
my home looking for something that has
nothing to do with it. I trust those
people implicitly. What I don't trust
and it has nothing to do with the
distinguished members of this council or
our esteemed mayor. It is this is a
violation of the fourth amendment of the
constitution of the United States and we
weasle word our way around those
[clears throat] amendments and that's a
bad idea. I don't think there's too many
people in this state that want me we
anyone weasling around the second
amendment of the constitution. The first
amendment which is absolutely crucial to
all of our liberties is also something
we don't play games with. We shouldn't
play with any of them. So I would say
I'm not here to say or to disagree with
this ordinance uh that it needs to be
wordsmith and improved. I think that it
is a violation of the fourth amendment.
It is at least a violation of the spirit
of the fourth amendment. Um
the right of the people to be secure in
their persons, houses, papers, and
effects against unreasonable searches
and seizures shall not be violated. And
I think if you started with that as your
founding statement uh and then looked
for a solution to the problem um maybe
you could come up with a different
solution. Perhaps there is a problem
that needs to be addressed. But walking
dangerously close to the free to the
rights guaranteed in our constitution is
is perhaps not the best way to go. Thank
you for your thank you for the
opportunity to speak.
>> Thanks for being here this evening.
Thank you.
>> Good evening, mayor and members of
council. Lee Filer and my Lee Filer
capacity uh ward one. Um
I'm here respectfully to oppose this
this ordinance 1.28. Cheyenne has always
been a city that values common sense,
personal responsibility, limited
government. Ordinance 1.28 28 moves away
from these principles by expanding
regulation in a way that creates more
bureaucracy, more enforcement costs, and
more uncertainty for residents and small
businesses.
My concern is not just with the
ordinance it tends to do, but with what
it could do.
Once a new authority is created, it
rarely shrinks.
Vague or overly broad ordinances often
lead to inconsistent enforcement,
unintended penalties, and decisions made
or being made farther away from the
people that they affect.
The city already has tools to address
legitimate concerns through existing
ordinances and state law. Before
creating new rules, we should ask, is
this truly necessary? Is it clearly
defined?
and does this and does it respect the
rights and freedoms of Cheyenne
residents.
Good government means solving real
problems without overcorrecting.
Ordinance 1.28 risks creating a solution
in search of a problem while adding
long-term costs and restrictions that
the public did not ask for.
I encourage the council to slow this
process down, seek more public input,
and consider whether this ordinance
aligns with this with Cheyenne's values
of fairness, transparency, and limited
government. For this reasons, I ask you
to vote no on this ordinance, and I
didn't want to bring up all the
constitutional stuff because it's been
brought up quite a bit. So, that's all I
have to say. Mayor, and council, thank
you.
>> Nice having you here again tonight.
Thank you,
>> sir. Did you want to speak? Wonderful.
Bring that microphone right in front of
you if you would. You know, this is you
can tell this is a generational thing.
You know, I would write this out on a
piece of paper, but all you guys are
done all in the technology. I'm
impressed.
>> Yeah.
Second,
I just lost it.
>> That's why I write it out.
>> I know.
If you want, we can take someone else
while you're looking for it.
>> Anybody else want to speak?
Somebody online. We'll take that one
first. Who do we have? Jennifer,
>> Mr. Alan Sheldon. You should be able to
unmute yourself.
>> Mr. Sheldon, all these people showed up
and you didn't. What happened tonight?
You know, I had an appointment that's
coming up soon, so I kind of had other
obligations.
>> Yeah. But yes, Alan Sheldon Ward, too.
Uh, Mr. Mayor, Council, thank you for
the opportunity to speak in opposition
to the ordinance. Um, I had speaking
notes prepared on my laptop in this
case. Um, but so many people already had
covered the points that I was going to
discuss. Um, so in the interest of time,
I'll just ask that the council vote no
on this ordinance. Thank you.
>> We'll just call that ditto. Thank you,
sir.
Jennifer, do you have any more?
>> Welcome, sir.
>> I have no other hands raised at this
time. Oh,
>> I got one, but go ahead.
>> We'll let John go first.
>> Welcome, sir.
>> John Pulse, ward one. Mr. Mayor, city
council. Um, as somebody who's been
had had a lot of my time wasted dealing
with administrative people who have
personally threatened me and bothered me
at home and in my house, I feel that
this ordinance is an overreach. Um,
there's too much gray area where it
needs to be worded specifically. Um,
there there's too many problems involved
in the ordinance where there could be
overreach. It just needs to be re
rewarded. As far as the abandoned house
thing, I 100% agree. I've got a problem
right next door to my home that has an
abandoned house where we had several
people arrested. So, I don't agree
disagree with it 100%, but the wording
on it is extremely vague and needs to be
rewarded in several ways. So, that's all
I have to say.
>> Thanks for being here, John. Did you
find it? All right.
>> I'm Sam McInness. I'm in W three.
Let me tell you why administrative wars
are the pinnacle of modern
governance. The kind of innovation that
will usher in the glorious area of
privacy is just a quaint relic of the
dark age. Like a rotary phone,
unmonitored thoughts. Picture this. The
world where bureaucrats, those unsung
heroes in ill-fit suits, skip the pesky
judiciary and just rubber stamp their
way into your house, your business, your
very soul. Why bother with judges who
might heaven forbid demand actual
evidence or due process that so 24th
century or 20th century so inefficient
so human supportive support
administrative warns because they
streamline justice into sleek automated
dystopia where your front door is
basically a revolving portal for
inspectors. Imagine waking up to the hum
of drones delivering your daily
compliance check. Did you recycle your
plastic fork correctly? Is your
thermostat set to the government
approved 68 degrees to combat climate
change? Or are they secretly plotting
against the planet? What administrative
warrants will eliminate is the chaos of
warrants requiring probable cause
instead of it's all about reasonable
suspicion interpretation by the
algorithm that knows you better than
your spouse. You're smart. refrigerator
will rat on you for buying too much
cheese. Boom. War issued [snorts] agents
at your door before they can say fourth
amendment. And let's not forget about
the economic boom. Every unwarranted
search creates jobs. More paper pushers
to fill reports. More surveillance tech
companies to install the mandatory home
cameras for your safety. Of course,
thriving black market for tinfoil hats
because hey, paranoid is a new
patriotism. In utopia, we'll be equal,
equally watched, equally compliant,
equally numb. No more messy debates
about rights, just blissful submission
to the all-seeing state. Who needs
freedom when you have efficiency?
>> Sir, did you want to speak,
please?
>> Please introduce yourself. We look
forward to it.
>> Mr. Mayor, my name is Caleb Wilkins. I
have historically been a resident of the
city of Cheyenne until fairly recently
when I moved into the county, have a
number of properties throughout wards in
the city, and would like to provide a
brief comment on the proposed ordinance
before us here today. [clears throat]
I must disclose that I've had a number
of interactions with code compliance and
I'm happy to say every single one with
no exception was positive. I have seen
instances where I wished code compliance
actually had more authority and there
have been instances I've run into with
clients through my work as an attorney
here in town where I have certainly wish
the fire department had more authority.
However, this is not the solution. While
it was in a slightly different context,
I would like to go back to Federalist
51. Um, this is the famous of men were
angels.
It may be a reflection on human nature
that such devices should be necessary to
control the abuses of government. But
what is government itself? But the
greatest of all reflections on human
nature. If men were angels, no
government would be necessary. And if
angels were to govern men, neither
external nor internal controls on
government would be necessary. In
framing a government which is to be
administered by men over men, the great
difficulty lies in this. You must first
enable the government to control the
governed and in the next place oblige it
to control itself. In this instance, I
believe there are specific factual
scenarios where a warrant would be
helpful, would probably even advance the
police um power of the city. But
unfortunately, this ordinance as written
is vastly over broad. I'm not here to
argue the Fourth Amendment or the Fourth
Amendment is adopted by the Wyoming
Constitution. As Mr. Crossman pointed
out, there are some differences there,
subtle as they may be. I am here to say
that this ordinance allows far too much
power and far too much opportunity for
overreach. I believe that Wyoming is
very different than Portland, than New
York or Denver. And with our current
citizenry, our current laws, and our
current, I I even would say castle
doctrine, this could very easily,
particularly with the no knock language,
introduce a very real danger to our code
enforcement officers as written. Um, and
some of those people, I would dare say,
are friends, and I would not want to see
them in danger. As a result, I think it
would be easier and more prudent to
start from scratch. This is so overroad.
I would be happy in my private capacity
as an attorney to sit down with Mr.
Brody or other individuals within the
city and donate some time proono along
with a number of other attorneys I work
with to try and tailor this to fit the
needs of Wyoming without being overroad
and also allowing the government
officials to do their job efficiently
and protect the citizenry of this great
city. Thank you,
>> Mr. Mayor.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Mr. Wilkins. Nice to see you.
You're in fact suing the state of the
city of Cheyenne, aren't you? On behalf
of
>> Point of order, Mr. Mayor, this has
nothing to do with this uh ordinance and
public hearing.
>> I would agree. Second. Yes,
>> I agree.
>> And unfortunately, the representative
party rules would prohibit me from
commenting on that.
>> No, they would not. Point of order, Mr.
Mayor.
>> It's a public Mr. Wolf. Point of order.
Mr. has nothing to do with the business
at hand. Thank you.
>> I second that. Point of order, Mayor.
>> Mr. Mayor, it has everything to do with
this gentleman's credibility uh in front
of us. Point of order, Mr. Mayor. Point
of order.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, we we've we've
we've got it under control. Thank you,
Mr. W. Thank you for being here this
evening,
>> Mr. Mayor. Were there any other
questions? I would be happy to stand for
question.
>> No, sir. Thank you.
>> Thank you, sir. And have a good evening.
>> You, too. [applause]
>> Anybody else who would like to testify
this evening? Anyone
online? Jennifer,
[clears throat]
>> they raise their hands and then they
take him down. Hold on just a minute.
Uh, Mr. Miller, you should be able to
unmute yourself.
>> Mr. Miller, welcome.
>> Yes. Hello. Can you hear me?
>> We can, sir.
>> Okay. Um, let's see here. Good evening,
council members. My name is Charles, and
I'm here to address chapter 128 of the
proposed ordinance. Um, it seems like a
lot of people have touched on a lot of
these points, but maybe they haven't.
Here a couple of the points I got. The
main point I wanted to make tonight is
simple though. The the chapter 128, uh,
it violates the law. Specifically, it
violates two critical legal fa
frameworks. Wyoming state statute and
the United States Constitution,
particularly the Fourth Amendment. Um,
there are actually four major violations
in this ordinance. First, it's the wrong
judge. The ordinance uses a municipal
judge instead of a district court judge,
which directly violates Wyoming statute
section 35-7-1046.
Second, there's no pre-notice. It allows
secret warrants without notifying the
property owner, which violates the
Supreme Court's ruling in the Patel
case. Third, no hearing. It issues
warrants exparte, that means secretly
without the owner present to argue their
case. Fourth, wrong scope. It uses fire
code authority for non-fire issues like
weeds and zoning violations. Let me walk
through each of those in detail. Let's
start with violation number one, state
law, Wyoming statute section 35-7-1046
is crystal clear. It requires that
district court judge must issue these
administrative warrants. But city
ordinance 1.28 uses a municipal judge
instead, a judge who is hired and fired
by the city manager. The result, the
city is lowering the standard set by
state law. This makes the ordinance void
abinitio. That's a legal term meaning
invalid from the very start. You cannot
use a lower standard than what the state
requires. That's not how the law works.
Now, um let's talk about violations two
and three. Secret searches. In 2015, the
Supreme Court ruled in city of Los
Angeles vers Patel that administrative
searches require two things. Pre-notice
to the owner, a pre-hering before a
neutral judge. But chapter 1.28 allows
the city to skip both notice and hearing
if they claim it would frustrate the
purpose of the inspection. Here's the
reality. Announcing a search for weeds
doesn't make the weeds disappear. This
exception effectively allows secret
searches for every code violation.
That's unconstitutional. The Fourth
Amendment protects us from exactly this
kind of government overreach. Violation
number four, misusing the fire code. The
Wyoming fire code, title 35-9111,
is limited in scope. It applies only to
structures that are especially liable to
fire. But the city is using this fire
code authority for weeds, not a fire
issue. Junk, not a fire issue. Zoning
violations, not a fire issue. Building
code violations, not a fire issue. The
result, the city is exceeding the
authority granted by state fire codes.
You can't take a narrow power and expand
it to cover everything that's not legal.
So, in conclusion, here's my request.
Vote no on chapter 1.28 28. If you
genuinely need enforcement powers, then
draft a legal ordinance. One that uses
district judges as required by state
statute. One that requires notice and
hearing as required by the constitution.
One that limits enforcement to actual
fire hazards as required by fire uh code
scope. This isn't about preventing
enforcement. It's about doing it
legally. Thank you for your time.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Question clarification.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Um thank you, Mor. Uh thank you, sir.
testimony. Could you provide the number
for that? Uh, regarding the circuit
court judge versus municipal court
judge. I didn't write fast enough the uh
number.
>> Mr. Miller, are you still there?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Uh, okay. I'm sorry. What
was that?
>> Uh, thank you, sir. Just the uh the the
co the uh Wyoming state law, the number
for regarding the circuit judge versus
municipal judge.
>> Uh, the district it's actually district
court judge. Um, but it's SEC Wyoming
statute section 35-7-1046.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> It requires that a district court judge
must issue these administrative
warrants.
>> Jennifer, do you have any others online?
>> Yes, Mr. Jacobson, you can unmute
yourself.
>> Welcome, Mr. Jacobson.
>> Good evening.
Thank you, Mayor City Council, the
opportunity to speak.
Um,
I became aware of this through reading
some articles or reading in Next Door
and some of you've been on there,
including uh, Councilman Wolf.
And um because of this, I went back and
I went to the city council meeting and
the video, read the minutes
of number of the first reading. Also
went to the public service committee
meeting and looked at that video.
I've also noted that there's three
sponsors on this bill, this ordinance,
and I've yet to hear anybody explain to
me why this is necessary.
The public service committee meeting did
have I think the assistant uh
fire marshal who did a very great
presentation
but it was very interesting because he
said you know we had this problem after
the fire went out we weren't sure what
we were going to do and then the next
thing we wanted to go back but the fire
popped up so we got to go back anyway
because we didn't need anything. I've
yet to hear one example, one example,
date, time, name, dress, or anything to
say this is a situation that occurred.
I've never heard anything to say that
this needed to be done. And if it did
need to be done, how did you resolve the
issue or is it an ongoing problem? In my
neighborhood, I have places that you can
visually see in the city that there's a
problem and the city's done near a thing
about them. Why is that? I don't know
why you need to have a thing like this.
You need to come into somebody's house.
I'm pretty sure I don't have any problem
my house because it's been was built by
and I've had two of them. I still have
in the city of Blair City of Cheyenne.
So I find it interesting that I have had
no one tell me why has to be done done.
And as you really look at it says
um
it's for administrative to reasonably
and necessary under any ordinance or
other law. In other words, this is so
broad that if somebody thinks that
there's a violation of any ordinance or
any other law that they're supposed to
be able to get a administrative warrant
and go into your house.
Um,
when you look at the ordinance,
the very last part of it talks about
building safety. It's B and it says
building safety department staff under
the direction of chief building officer
perform all plan review building
inspections functions including
>> is up can you conclude for me please?
>> Well the point that I'm making it makes
no sense
and I think it's time to come to grips
with this that this was poorly written
and if you have a problem write a law an
ordinance that's specific for that. If
you got abandoned buildings, do that. If
you got a problem with the stats in the
in the buildings downtown that are a
problem, then
>> thank you. Write law so you can cover
that rather than including 61,000 people
in the city of Cheyenne to be dealt
with.
>> Thank you.
>> Appreciate it.
Anybody else want to speak this evening?
Jennifer, another one.
>> I have uh Mr. Miller with his hand
raised again.
>> We've already heard from Mr. Miller, so
let's go on to the people here in the
audience. Ma'am, welcome.
>> It's nice to have you back again.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> Bring that microphone down a little bit
for me.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor and Council. Um, I
came here tonight because I was
interested in what might be going on and
it's been really quite interesting. Uh,
my suggestion is that you kind of sit
down and redo it and figure out what's
wrong with you with the proposal and
let's see what we can do with it. I like
um kind of sort of uh things that need
to be done and let's sit down and talk
about it. Thank you very much for your
your at least attention to things.
>> Appreciate you coming again this
evening. Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Thank you so much, Mr.
Mayor and Council.
>> Can you uh repeat your name for the
record, please?
>> Oh, yeah. My name is Marin Stalp and I
just bought a new house in Sun Valley.
They uh renovated it and I live at 455
East 13th Street.
>> Must be new. You had to stop and think
about that for a minute. So that's
that's a really new house.
>> I had to look at uh Dr. Aldridge. We
have the same house number. [laughter]
I've lived in Chad all my life and all
of these things that has happened, all
of these things that could happen,
been there, done that, seen that, and it
wasn't all that exciting to have to have
this huge
ordinance.
>> Well, we're so happy you were here again
tonight. Thank you.
>> If you'd like to have any examples, we
could do it off.
>> There you go. And then you're going to
go, "Oh my gosh, thank you so much.
>> Anyone else?"
>> All right, last call.
All right, hearing none, we'll move on
to uh Mr. Crave for a motion.
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
public services committee is to approve
on second reading and I so move.
>> Second. Seconded by Dr. Emmens.
[clears throat and cough]
>> All right. Discussion for members of the
governing body.
>> Dr. Aldridge.
>> Yes, sir. Well, thank you, Mayor
Collins. Um, and thank you to everybody
who has come out tonight and for those
of you that have given us military
service. Thank you for your service as
well that mentioned that in your
testimony. Um, I have taken a copious
quantity of notes. I've heard from many
of you um over the last week. Um I did
um ask a lot of questions at the public
service committee um and Andrew Dyshorn,
our fire chief, was um kind enough to
answer those questions. I've also done a
lot of learning and research since that
time. And um I
really believe that um if this is
something that um is really felt to be
needed and I and the comment was made at
public services committee that this is
probably um less common than um rather
than more common that it probably needs
to have some amendments made and to be
reworked. Um but um I share some of your
concerns. Um, I also,
um, know that while, you know, this
council and our building officials and
our fire department have good
intentions, um, sometimes we don't
always think about the unintended
consequences or the councils and the
officials that are going to follow us.
And, um, I agree with many of you that,
um, I think we may be putting our city
employees at risk with the stand your
ground law and the, uh, you know, castle
law. um if they would approach a door um
and try and enter a property uh with an
administrative warrant. I'm going to do
some more research on the 3 point the
357 104.6 state statute um and some of
the legal cases that were cited tonight.
Um but the only way that I will be able
to support this um piece of legislation
is if it were to be amended um
significantly for abandoned properties
or things that are unoccupied. um and
over given proof of time and uh actually
with more documentation. I just think we
need to raise the bar. So for that
reason, I'll be a no vote tonight.
>> Anyone else in the governing body?
>> Dr. Emmans.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Um I do I have a
question. First of all, the ordinance
that we're talking about, we're we're
really just amending the existing
ordinance. Is that correct? The whole
ordinance is new.
>> Mr. Brody,
>> uh John Brody, city attorney. So, uh the
city code all already allows through the
adoption of the um international
building codes and the international
fire code uh for the authorized
individual to seek an administrative
warrant. Um however, those codes specify
that they have to seek that warrant um
in accordance with the procedures
specified by law. effectively. Cheyenne
does not have those procedures specified
by law. So, there's a disconnect. So,
what the first part of the ordinance
does is create a new uh section of
municipal code putting out the the
process through which she would obtain a
warrant and then we amend um the chief
building officials authority to allow
for uh him to apply for these types of
warrants. And then we create the
authority for the fire chief to apply as
well.
>> So, just to clarify, Mr. Mayor, um so
chapter 1.28 28 is brand new,
>> Mr. Mayor. Yes.
>> Okay.
Um,
thank you, Mr. Mayor. I have I want to
make a comment. Um,
first of all, and I know this is going
to be met with some different takes. I
don't believe that anyone in fire
department in building in the city
council anywhere in government at the
city level has any interest in going
into anybody's bathroom and looking in
cupboards or anything like that. This is
specific to
this was brought to us specific to a
dangerous health and safety issue. And I
agree completely with um
Councilwoman Aldrich that obviously we
need to take this back and look at the
specifics,
but I also heard very clearly from
several people that there is an issue.
We do have an issue with some safety of
buildings that are potentially a threat
and we need to take care of that. We
can't just because people were upset
about the first take on this just scrap
the whole thing.
So, um, I'm going to vote for this to go
forward so that we can clean it up, come
at it from the right perspective so it
does address the issue, the problem that
has been brought forward.
So, I just want to put that out there.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Three. Want
to thank everybody for your public
comment both online and here because
remember, you guys are our bosses. we
represent you. Um, I will be a no vote
because as stated, if it applied to
banned property, it' be a different
story. It does not apply just to abandon
property. You guys correctly said it
applies to all properties, and I do have
an issue with that. And again, the
Wyoming Constitution is stronger. I read
some of those uh court cases that were
mentioned, and I agree. This does take
it a step too far. Okay? crossing that
line in the sand. And the other reason
I'm a no vote if it needs to be heavily
amended than is a poorly written
ordinance. So that's why I'd be better
off just to scrap it, start from
scratch, focus on abandoned buildings
andor unlawfully occupied abandoned
buildings. Focus on that, there wouldn't
be any issues. But now there's plenty of
issues. Scrap it and let's start from uh
scratch again. We got plenty of time. We
don't have the 40-day or 20-day window
like the legislature. Thank you, Mr.
Mayor.
>> Mr. Escoel.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you, since
this is second reading, I'm going to
give the sponsors in the committee
opportunity to work on it. Um, there's
been a lot of talk about abandoned
buildings and uh I'm going to give you a
little bit of real life experience that
I had.
Uh my brother, he's a Vietnam vet,
was living alone in our parents' old
house.
Uh the fireplace became detached from
the house.
And as a a brother, I was concerned
about his well-being, as were my other
brothers and my sisters.
So, um,
I went to appliance and I had my
brother's,
um, fireplace red tagged, so he couldn't
use it. But before that, the cinders
that were coming out of that fireplace
were not landing on his house. They were
landing on your house.
And if we knew something that was wrong
there, didn't do nothing about it, and
your house and all your worldly
possessions burned down,
would you come to us and ask us why we
didn't do nothing about that?
I think you'd be a lot more pissed off
than you are now.
That's why I think this thing is needs
to be worked on. Now,
uh temporarily our brother is is okay,
but uh I think his days are are
numbered. And uh uh like I said, he he
served in the Vietnam War.
Um
and I love my brother very much.
And um so I have real real life
experiences how this could actually save
people's lives.
And I stick to that triangle of being a
public servant and staying between that
triangle of health, welfare, and safety
is for the citizens.
And that's you.
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
>> Anyone else in the governing body? Mr.
Wolf.
>> Mr. Mayor. Thank you. Through you.
I've lived in this city for 51 years.
My wife's family has been here for a
hundred years.
I've heard people come tonight and talk
about Wyoming values
and I dare say that probably
I've seen plenty and know plenty about
Wyoming values.
I see a lot of fear in this room.
You're afraid of government. You're
afraid of each other. You're afraid of
us.
You're afraid of the future. You're
telling us that gosh, what might happen
with some elected official into the
future? Well, guess what? We don't know.
We don't know what they're going to do.
All we know is what we should do
and what you should think about. And
Councilman Escoel makes a great point,
which is if you have a house next door
to you and your neighbor is not taking
care of it,
what are you going to do? You're going
to call the city and you're going to ask
the city to go and fix it. And so when
you make that phone call, what answer do
you want?
Because you could get one of two
answers. One answer you could get is,
"We're fully aware of the problem. We've
been working hard on it. We now have the
right to actually go get a warrant and
go and inspect the property
or do you want an answer that says, you
know, we're really we are aware of this.
We know there's a problem, but you know,
the board of realers don't want us to be
able to go inspect that property.
There are some citizens in the town who
don't want us to go to that property.
So, we don't have the authority to do
that. So, I'm sorry. And if that house
catches on fire and burns yours down at
the same time, don't call the city to
complain about that.
So, where are we from here? There is a
>> Wolf, can I pause you for just a second?
Ladies and gentlemen, we listen very
respectfully while you spoke with us. We
tried to. Okay. So, let's give uh the
city council
>> apologize. Let's let's do the same.
Okay. Thank you so much,
>> Mr. Wolf. I apologize.
>> No, thank you.
>> There's a lot of misunderstanding about
this.
>> Ma'am. Ma'am. Ma'am, I'm going to have
to ask you to leave if you don't sit
respectfully, please. I I
>> called it I called him out of order.
>> Did I not? Thank you. Let's show
respect. Thank you.
>> Well,
I'll summarize.
The law on this is actually quite clear.
Starts with the Supreme Court case in
the 1960s,
goes all the way up to today. Courts
around the country have found that
administrative warrants are valid if
they comply with the Fourth Amendment.
And the Fourth Amendment requirements
are that you get a warrant. And that's
exactly what this proposed rule does.
Now, can we improve it? Sure. We have a
couple weeks to do that. We have another
another committee meeting and then we
have another council meeting. So, if you
have specific changes you want to
propose to us, please come and bring
them forward. Um, but we don't need to
hear more discussion about how this is
government overreach. That tells us
nothing.
We know all that. Come in and tell us
exactly what you would like to see done.
I'm going to vote in favor of moving
this on to third reading. Thank you, Mr.
Mayor.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Mayor. I just had a point
of information. Um, the email from the
board of realtors, wasn't that just a
request a postponement and not for or
against?
>> The email I got, sir, was for
postponement.
>> Thank you.
>> Anyone else in the governing body?
>> Yeah, Mr. Mr. Secret,
>> very briefly, Mr. Mayor. Um, we've had a
lot of lot of discussion tonight. A lot
of it's very enlightening. I appreciate
that. Um,
I don't I don't think I'm ready to give
up on this. Um, so I'm going to support
it tonight. Um, but I do hope that the
committee um can find some common ground
with the issues you've brought up. So,
um, I'm going to I'm going to support it
tonight and we'll see what we can do
with two weeks. Thank you very much,
>> Dr. Emmens.
>> Um, thank you, Mr. Mayor. I wanted to
say one other thing. I'm the new
oncoming chair for the public service
commission or committee. So, please do
let us know, come to the meeting, let us
know how you would like, you know, any
improvements that you see so that we can
look at building a better document. So,
you're all being invited right now to
have direct input into that. So, thank
you,
>> Dr.
Thank you. Um, Mer Yeah, [laughter]
happy happy doctor. Um, Mayor Collins
through you. I would just like to remind
everyone too that we also have council
and coffee this Saturday morning from 9
to 11 at Dosbog. And, um, if you have
some suggestions, uh, we would be more
than happy to hear those then. Um, and I
would uh and I don't see I think Caleb
may have left, but um any of those of
you that are attorneys that are willing
to give us some ideas and um thoughts
about how we can improve this and make
it something that will um be able to
take care of the properties that all of
us are concerned about um that we know
are a public safety hazard um or are
abandoned or unoccupied. Um we would
love to hear that. So, and um I know
we've got a big contingency of realators
tonight. So, um thanks for all that you
guys do and for bringing forward your
good ideas.
>> All right, Mr. Leborn, did you want to
speak?
>> Thank you, [clears throat] Mr. Mayor. We
all received a uh policy brief from the
fire department.
Could we have the chief come explain
briefly what his concerns are laid out
in this memo?
Chief,
>> thank you, sir.
>> Uh, good evening, mayor, uh, members of
council. Andrew Dyhorn, fire chief for
Shine Fire Rescue. U, you just wanted to
summary your description of the brief I
shared with you, sir. Um, through you,
Mr. Mayor. Um what I basically shared
with uh city council member just for
everybody's information tonight um was
kind of the need for administrative
inspection warrants in the fire service.
Um this goes back to some US Supreme
Court rulings um and where warrantless
searches were actually done. Um and all
those court cases were inadmissible. The
evidence was inadmissible. Um so just
trying to provide a clear operational
policy for our folks. Um what these two
things basically does is um provide for
fire code inspections. Um under the
international fire code uh 2024 which is
adopted by this governing body um we
want to enter commercial occupancies um
to do those regularly scheduled um fire
inspections. Um those are routine. We do
follow-up inspections. Um we gain
consent from the business owners to come
on their property. We work with business
owners while we walk their property. Um
that's a pretty uh typical uh
interaction for our fire service folks.
Um there are some times though where we
are denied entry to certain parts of a
building um for for whatever reason
they're they're worried about security
or proprietary information, things like
that. And um we continue to work through
those conflicts with the business owners
as we as we can. Um if we can't work
through that conflict, um basically
we're stuck and we can't fulfill the
need of our fire code. Um what state
statute tells us as far as what we need
to do to inspect those buildings. Um,
just for everybody's information, we do
not inspect residential properties
unless we are invited to do a home
safety inspection, but that is not
enforceable by our fire code either.
It's just guidance um for somebody's
home. Um, the second aspect of this is
our fire investigations. Uh, those are
very complex uh things that we have to
to work through. Sometimes we don't know
where the property owner is. We can't
find them um to finish out some of these
uh investigations. So, um, often when
the property owners are there and they
show up, they want us to investigate the
fire. Um, we get, um, consent to
investigation form signed and work with
the property owners continually for
sometimes weeks and months to try to
determine what caused a fire, work with
insurance companies, everything. So, um,
but sometimes we can't find property
owners. Um, and so at that point, we're
also kind of stuck. Once the emergency
uh ends and we leave that property, we
can no longer go back to said property
um without some type of tool such as
this administration inspection warrant
to complete that out if we if we can't
find the person if we can't gain their
consent. So, um that's just the the few
things I provided there. Obviously, this
has to go before a judge if we're going
to request this. We have to have a
purpose um administrative probable
cause. It's just if we find something
criminal in nature with a fire
investigation, we already pause, back
up, and let law enforcement be involved.
That's already our standing operating
procedure. So, um, hopefully that was a
good summary for you all and kind of the
information I, uh, had provided and
would stand for any more questions, sir.
>> Followup.
>> Do you have a followup, Mr. Leurn?
>> Yes, I do. Uh, Chief, could you explain
a little bit about the recent
certification that our department
received and through the process that
you uh work through to uh demonstrate
that we have one of the finest fire
departments uh in the country,
>> Chief? Uh through you, Mr. Mayor. Yes,
that would be the uh accreditation
process we work through. Is that what
you're referring to, sir?
>> Yes.
>> From the Centers for Public Safety
Excellence. Um so yes, we uh we obtained
and were awarded that um back April 1st
of uh 2025. Um pretty major milestone
for our fire department to um ensure
we're continually improving our
operations, what we do, how we respond
in the community. Um most of it is
communitydriven as far as u gaining
information of the services we need to
provide for the community. Um we do a
complete full self assessment of our uh
fire department. and it's 475 pages. If
you would at all would like to read it,
um I can provide that as well. Um we did
a uh communitydriven strategic plan back
in 2023 to really listen to our
community and get feedback on where we
should really uh dig into and enforce
some of the the resources we provide and
the services we provide for the
community. Um, and then lastly, the last
o other piece is that we look at uh risk
in our community. Uh, full spectrum of
risk and and and where we're seeing the
problems in our community and how we
respond to those problems. We make
recommendations. We track um call times,
response times, number of inspections,
all those all those things and how we're
actually affecting that risk is what we
need to show.
And for the audience sake, there was at
that time just over 300 fire departments
in the world that had received that kind
of accreditation. So there might be what
340 now in the world, something like
that. So it's uh it was literally 40,000
hours worth of uh work by our fire
department to achieve that accreditation
and then they have to uh continue that
every five years they get re-evaluated
to uh to maintain that. It was something
we're really proud of. Mr. Leborn.
>> Uh thank you, Chief. I'm wondering if
the the chief building official could
step up and explain how uh he works with
and interprets the uh international
property maintenance code which we have
adopted and is online if anyone's
interested. This is a very complete and
complex
uh code that really lays out all the
specific reasons why and how the chief
building inspector has the ability to
evaluate problems. Could you uh help us
with that?
>> Tona, can you let kind of share maybe
how you would see this working for your
department?
>> Uh Mr. Mayor, uh, members of the council
to, um, Councilman Labour's questions.
Um,
>> identify.
>> My name is Ton Palmer. I'm the chief
building official for the city of
Cheyenne. I've served in the position
for coming up on five years now with
this jurisdiction, address 21101 O'Neal.
Um the council uh the city uh through
adoption and ordinance has adopted the
international codes and they stem they
range from the building code to the fire
code to the property maintenance code to
plumbing HVAC all of that is what's
adopted. Every one of these model codes
has the language within it that gives
either the fire code official or the
chief building official the authority to
gain entrance to structures where it is
and there is probable cause that a life
safety health and welfare issue exists.
The property maintenance code uh again
another adopted code takes that to
another level where we are dealing with
abandoned structures. Structures that
have been left or are dilapitated to
such an extent that they do pose a life
safety risk to the public or to the
inhabitants of that structure. Um the
codes clearly lay out when the building
official or the fire code official can
request that warrant. they clearly lay
out what is required and it clearly lays
out that there needs to be a path
through the city's uh official channels
or or through the legal processes that
make that possible for these officials.
Um
Mr. Lake, is that answering the question
that you had asked, sir?
>> Uh Mr. Mayor, follow up. Um, can you
tell me, uh, Tono, how many, uh, of
these health and safety inspections you
do and, uh, how often you resolve the
issue and how often you expect to ever
ask for a warrant,
>> Mr. Mayor, through you to uh, Councilman
Leborn. um
a building official in any jurisdiction
deals with this hundreds and thousands
of times over their career. That is our
job. That is the nature of what we do.
The instances that arise where a warrant
is required would come down to um a
building permit is issued, a uh the work
that's being performed is not code
compliant. Therefore, a stop work order
has to be issued and we cannot gain
compliance. That would be one instance
where this would come up. In my career
of doing this, I have done it again five
years here. I've done it approximately
five to six years in another
jurisdiction 11 years. I have had to do
this one time or I've needed the avenue
one time for a red tag scenario.
um in my time with the city is uh
enforcement of the property maintenance
code. This has come up maybe three to
five times where we could not address
the issue and gain access to the
structure. It was not and it never has
been because I was denied access. I have
always been able to have discussion with
homeowners and been able to do that. It
has always come up to properties that
are um vacant, not being able to get in
there and we are getting calls from the
public. In the opinion or well, not even
in the opinion, sir, in the intention of
the code is to be able to allow the
building official who is answerable to
the citizens and to this council to be
able to gain access to address those
life safety issues to protect them. We
are always dealing with the neighbor. We
are always dealing with the
neighborhood. And
the people in this room, myself
included, if it's my neighbor, we all
need an avenue to be able to get these
problems addressed so that life safety,
health, welfare can be taken care of.
>> Thank you, M.
[clears throat]
>> Yes, Mr. Mayor. I have a few other
comments to make,
>> please.
This is something that I've dealt with
uh personally uh as a citizen,
as a gadfly, as a council person,
and as a individual who has many times
been out on the site of abandoned
buildings and dangerous structures
with the guidance of these
professionals.
So, I can tell you that unfortunately
the reality that we live in today
means that as unbelievable as it might
seem, people are abandoning more
property.
There are old buildings that are pretty
much had it.
And so, h how do you deal with them? And
I want to remind everybody here, and I'm
sorry so many people left,
that property rights come with property
responsibilities.
Very, very much so. And the
responsibility is to deal with these
individuals who we've heard testimony
tonight seem to be doing a pretty good
job.
This fear seems to come from some
unidentified source, whether it's
Boulder or San Francisco or
Pennsylvania.
Right here in Cheyenne, Wyoming, these
individuals that just spoke to you are
not unelected bureaucrats.
And that term has been a in my emails
practically without exception, unelected
bureaucrats.
So the conclusion that I reach is
evidently there are individuals that
want us
the elected officials to be interpreting
these codes
because if you're calling them
bureaucrats I'm calling them public
servants
and I'm calling them people who are
trained
extensively
and have put in a lot of time and work
on these issues and it is something that
uh might not be something that everybody
has to deal with,
but I was just looking at the house
earlier this afternoon.
It's been abandoned for a year and a
half.
And I suggest to you that the property
rights of the children that live across
the alley from that house need to be
taken into consideration.
Their mother called me
I went over there. Uh the building was
boarded up. I was over there this
afternoon. Well, evidently those
access had been gained to that building.
And those individuals who are um very
sad, very desperate,
and probably sick um are back.
And that is just one example.
There are examples that the compliance
department can tell you about of
properties that we've been working on
literally for years, four years, five
years to get that dealt with. Now, that
mortgage might have been sold and sold
again until we don't know where it went.
that property owner might live far away
and not care very much about our our
properties and our city. So, I want to
emphasize this.
I'm not an attorney, but I have a lot of
experience here with something that
no one should have to have that kind of
experience.
And many times, many times these
individuals who were alleged to be
unelected bureaucrats
work through a problem
and get that house flipped and people
back in it or buildings that are half
burnt. I mean, these are serious
problems and I believe that the language
that we're looking at here um just
really isn't the type of
there is a big difference and I
appreciate the efforts of our city
attorney's office here. There is a big
difference between the plain meaning of
the language that we use and legal terms
and how those legal terms go up the
ladder to the Constitution. And I want
to close with this.
When I raised my hand and took an oath
here,
that's for me to interpret
and I take it very seriously and I
assume everyone else does. And so I
really don't think others should be
saying that I'm violating the oath, my
oath, because I'm not.
and any of you that want to go and look
at some of these problem areas
and I assume that uh we could get some
assistance from these trained
professionals
might give you some insight into this
problem
and it goes way back and we have worked
diligently
to develop a code
that is interpreted by these individuals
that is very very very rare fairly going
to need a warrant.
But I'll tell you that we do need and
members of the council, I think we're
going to be looking at that in our
upcoming budget.
Where are we going to find the money
to demolish these properties and how do
we work through that process to acquire
the title to that deed?
Oh, we've done it a couple times, but it
has taken years
and and that is a really serious matter.
And if you
nobody wants to live next to the in a
neighborhood. This this is about
property values
and it isn't something most people pay
much attention to, but we have mansions
that are abandoned.
We have structures that no one's lived
in for quite a while that are falling
down that need to go. And we have
homes in every ward and neighborhood
that amazingly, unbelievably have been
turned into
something that clearly falls outside the
law. So I just want to emphasize this. I
can understand
that at this particular time in our
culture, in our country, in our world.
It is uh
very concerning to me and it certainly
is concerning to me about my house, my
commercial property as well. But these
individuals
don't deserve to be called unelected
bureaucrats
and and the work that they do. bless you
>> is open to anyone's consideration and
and certainly you can talk to them, you
can talk to us. I look forward to the
continuation of this. But I do truly
believe that we have to get away from
individuals interpretations of legal
terms and the constitution because I can
tell you I take that oath very seriously
and believe that what I have heard and
seen in regard to this process
very clearly comes from the Constitution
of the United States to the Constitution
of Wyoming to our city code in
absolutely legal manner. So, I
appreciate you listening to me and I'd
be glad to uh take you out and show you
some of these problems because when we
talk property rights, we've got to talk
property responsibilities that go along
with it. And I'm sure that everyone that
came here tonight
exercises their property
responsibilities as I do, but there are
people that don't and we got to deal
with them. Thank you.
Mr. Wolf, did you have a comment, sir?
>> Yes. Thank you, Mayor Through You. Um,
I'd like to just uh support and amplify
a bit on uh Councilman Labor's uh
comments, which I think are very well
taken. Uh first of all,
we have a I've been on the council not
even two months now. I'm in fact the
only unelected bureaucrat up here.
Everybody else has been elected. Um, and
I don't consider myself much of a
bureaucrat,
but what I've learned in that time and
watching the city for as long as I've
lived here is that we have a very highly
professional
set of uh departments and department
leaders. I credit the mayor for uh a lot
of that, but we have a tremendously
professional fire department and police
department. We have an superb city
engineer who's sitting in front here
quietly and uh and a city attorney and a
treasurer. And it goes on and on. and
the degree to which you express all of
this great fear about them and about
what they're going to do. These are not
people who act irrationally.
They're not people who will act without
a lot of thought and study and concern
and consideration.
Uh and and so I'd ask you as you
consider your own remarks to us and as
you consider what we may do with this in
the next couple weeks that you give them
the credit that they're due and that
probably applies to people in the future
as well. Um so I want to I want to thank
the mayor. I apologize for being a bit
out of order. Uh Mr. Mayor. Um, I want
to thank Mr. Lelaybornne who has the
first time I met Pete Leborn. He was
over boarding up a uh
an abandoned house came and did just to
do that. Uh, that was decades ago and
he's been a friend of mine for a long
time. So, thank you, Mr. Mayor. Thank
you for this. Thank you all of you for
coming here. We encourage you to
continue to meet with us and talk with
us about this, but uh I think you have a
fear about this that is uh I think
exaggerated uh and largely unwarranted,
but nothing's perfect. and I've spent
more than 40 years practicing law and we
can fix just about any kind of proposed
ordinance um if we have uh uh the right
comments, the right suggestions and
people acting for the right motives.
>> Thank you.
>> Point of information, Mayor.
>> Yes.
>> Um two points of information I'd like to
have clarified for the public who may be
here in person or watching. Where would
they obtain the policy brief that was
provided for the governing body? Um if
they that was provided by the uh fire
department if they would like to see
what uh Chief Dorn was referring to.
>> Madam clerk, if we gave you a copy of
that, could we put that on as an
exhibit?
>> Mr. Mayor, if that is your wish, we can
put that on there.
>> We'll do that.
>> Thank you. And my second point of
information, um, I was just wanting and
really as clarification from our, uh,
building inspector when he was citing
the UDC and the, uh, international
property maintenance code, he talked
about health, safety, and welfare. And I
just want to clarify, does that read
health, safety, and welfare? All three
uh, parameters have to be met, or is it
health, safety, or welfare? just one of
those three parameters has to be met
because I think that's a pretty
significant difference um and raises the
bar or lowers the bar depending upon how
that is how that reads to can you
articulate that please
>> Mr. Mayor through to Dr. Charidge
the mandate from the codes is life,
safety, health and welfare.
>> So all all of those parameters have to
be met
or is or seek to be or sought to be met
based on that code. Not just one like
not just health or not just safety or
not just welfare but all those
parameters in totality.
>> Mr. Mayor to you ma'am the uh Dr. Sorry.
The codes as a whole are created to
promote all of those through minimum
standards as adopted.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other comments from members of the
governing body?
>> Mr. White, do you want to speak?
>> You've been so quiet tonight.
>> Yes, Mr. Mayor. Thank you. Lot of
information.
>> Yes, sir. [clears throat]
>> Um, I appreciate everybody who uh spoke
to us during public comment, both in
person and online. I also appreciate the
uh presentations made by our fire chief
and chief building official as well as
the uh
articulate comments made by my
colleagues. Um
I am a sponsor of this ordinance. Full
disclosure,
um based on what I've heard tonight, um
I I'm still going to support moving this
forward. I do think um we'll be putting
forward some amend amendments to uh
perhaps
clarify
uh some of the language uh based on the
suggestions uh that were made by some of
the folks here tonight. Um
but I will be mo I will be supporting it
tonight. I do think
and I and I think um this is really
important
the the proposed ordinance and granted
perhaps it does need to be a bit more
narrowly tailored, but when we talked
about that uh city uh the Hail versus
City of Laramie that the uh Wyoming
Supreme Court just decided last month,
we utilized that for this ordinance
because that decision ision said any
type of administrative warrant has to be
supported by evidence and it has to be
reviewed by a court and it can't be
rubber stamped. And I heard some
comments earlier that if by by engaging
in this it's just going to anybody can
go in anywhere it it'll be rubber
stamped and that's just not the case.
It's not. So, I think the ordinance
intent is to protect both public safety
and constitutional rights. I'm not an
attorney. I appreciate the um code that
was cited earlier saying it can't be a
municipal court judge. It has to be a
district court judge. I want to I want
to uh air that out and see if that is in
fact the case. If it is, we'll change
the language in the ordinance to comply
with that.
Um, but I will be supporting it moving
forward.
>> All right, last comments.
>> I see none. All right, the motion is
before us is to approve the ordinance on
second reading. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed?
>> No.
>> Dr. Aldridge, Mr. Moody, and Dr. Renie
are nos. The ordinance is approved on
second reading.
Do we need to take a fiveminut break,
Mr.
>> Esel?
>> We're going to take a fivem minute break
and and we'll come back.
Good news on sales.
That's funny right there.
What about Mr. Lelay?
It's interesting.
Hey, Rosanne.
>> You want to switch places?
>> We're taking a
[snorts]
Thank you, sir.
So you know I'm not
Out of order. Out of order.
was that kind of lawyer
that was saying
that's correct.
Yeah, that was very exciting.
Any
good news?
>> Was it
They say they're
>> so
we were never
Small
great
Oh,
Mr. Moody, I'm calling the meeting back
to order, sir.
>> Madame Clerk, read the next item,
please.
Number 11, ordinance, first reading,
annexing to the city of Cheyenne,
Wyoming, various tracks of land
completely surrounded by current city
limits situally
located south of Story Boulevard, east
of Powder House Road, north of Del Range
Boulevard, and west of Ridge Road.
>> We'll refer this item to the public
services committee. Number 12, ordinance
first reading, amending the official
zoning map of the city of Cheyenne,
establishing the zoning classifications
of AG agricultural and MR medium density
residential for land annex to the city
of Cheyenne, generally located south of
Story Boulevard, east of Powder House
Road, north of Del Range Boulevard, and
west of Ridge Road.
>> We'll assign this one to the public
services committee. Number 13, ordinance
first reading amending 5.7.3
accessory dwelling units of the Cheyenne
Unified Development Code to remove owner
occupancy and adjust parking
requirements for accessory dwellings and
making conforming amendments to the
definitions of an accessory dwelling and
semi-attached dwelling under 1.4.4
descriptions of uses of land and
buildings.
>> This one will also go to the public
services committee.
Next item is number 15. Resolution
adopting the amended 2025 to 2027 city
of Cheyenne comprehensive consolidated
plan and the amended 2025 annual action
plan as prepared by the Cheyenne Housing
and Community Development Office in
setting the public comment period and
public hearings for the plans. You know,
Cheyenne is blessed that we're an
entitlement um community from HUD and
those dollars are are taken care of
through our CDBG office and every year
they have to do an annual action plan
and any money that's turned back we have
to make an amendment to that. And so
that's what's before us today. Is there
anybody here to speak to that
hearing? None. Mr. Lebornne, may I have
a motion on number 15?
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of the
finance committee is to adopt and I so
move. second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Crave.
>> Comments for members of the governing
body.
>> Mr. Mayor,
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Mayor. Through you.
Um, again, I did vote no because of the
private equity, but just a question if
anybody's from there. Could you look
into the problems of private equity
firms buying up not only single family
homes, but residential areas? I know uh,
President Trump has actually come out to
make a federal ban of doing that
bipartisanly as well. Could you guys
look into that as well too because that
is a major issue now with housing
affordability across the country.
>> Mr. Moody, in this case, I think you're
conflating the issue. Um, the company
that we're dealing with uh has many
divisions. One of those divisions is a
private equity company, but the division
that we're working with to build the
homes, both Wasatch, and I apologize, I
can't remember the uh portable housing
group there. They're not owned, managed,
and they don't hold uh housing in an uh
a private equity firm. It just happens
to be one of the divisions of that
company.
>> I was just looking at
>> Turn your microphone on, sir.
>> Oh, thank you, Mr. Mury. I was looking
at from a whole perspective. Uh just
making sure it doesn't happen even
outside of that. That's all
>> understood. Anybody else on the
governing body hearing? None. All those
in favor, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And those opposed?
>> No. The uh resolution is adopted with
Mr. Moody. No.
>> Next. Next item is number 22A on page
four.
>> Agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and Ring Central LLC for providing
cloud-based enterprise telecom services
for all city departments and divisions.
>> You know, we had to take this one off of
the consent agenda. Um our aging
telephone system is no longer supported
and uh we found a company that would
support our our software. Oh, Tyler's
here. I don't need to tell the story.
You tell it.
Turn that microphone on, Tyler.
All right. Um, good evening, mayor and
members of council. My name is Tyler
Nelson. I'm with City IT. Um, Mr. Mayor,
through you, the request for approval
you have before you is concerning the
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and Ring Central LLC. Um, the city's
current on premise phone system has
reached end of life as support for the
software is expired and no longer being
developed.
Um, we wanted to remove this item from
the consent agenda due to the $65,000
amount that was approved in finance
committee last Tuesday on the 6th. The
amount the amount is the total to
satisfy the quote on page two that was
provided and the amount it looks to
spend the amount that amount is the
amount it looks to spend out of the
current fiscal year budget to get the
project started but the amount did not
represent the amount of the 36-month
term of the agreement. Um all city
council members have been supplied with
a supplementary cost breakdown page. Um,
this breakdown page includes monthly
reoccurring costs, hardware costs,
one-time costs, as well as free months
of service which reflect as discounts or
savings
um that can come with the subscription
over the term of the agreement. Um, I'm
here to field any questions if there are
any and I can answer those as best I
can.
>> Does anybody in the governing body have
a question for staff? Dr. Aldrich.
>> Uh, Mayor Collins through you. I'm
wondering um so um used to be in the
telecom business myself working for AT&T
and I'm just curious about um this is
for um is this for just landlines or
does this include cellular and uh the
phones that our employees carry along as
well as the desk phones.
>> Mr. Nelson Nelson,
>> Mr. Mayor through you uh to Councilwoman
Aldrich. Um
this this service includes the telephone
system the city uses backend. It does
not include cell service like Verizon
service. Does not include uh landline
service that would be provided through a
landline provider. It's basically our
onrem telephone service that we we
provide and we manage.
>> Basically phones be called PBX.
>> You could say it that way. Um desk
phones. um anything like that. It is a
cloud service. So we're we're migrating
from an on-prem installation to a
cloudbased service.
>> Thank you.
>> Anyone else?
>> Thank you, Todd. Appreciate it. Anyone
in the audience like to speak to the
agreement
hearing? None. Mr. Leborn on 22A.
[clears throat]
>> Mr. Mayor, the recommendation.
>> Would you turn your microphone?
>> Excuse me,
>> M. Mayor. I [snorts] move to amend the
total dollar amount.
>> Can I get a motion first and then we'll
>> Okay, Mr. Mayor, the recommendation of
the finance committee is to approve an
amount not to exceed $65,000 and I so
move.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Moody. Mr. Leborn.
>> Mr. Mayor, I move to amend the total
dollar amount of the contract to
$324,750
over 36 months.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Moody.
All right, we'll go back out to the
audience. We're We have a change in the
price. It's not just for the rest of
this fiscal year, but it's actually for
36 months. Anybody in the audience want
to speak to the amendment?
>> Jennifer, you have one?
>> Yep. I have a Mr. Miller with his hand
raised.
>> All right, Mr. Miller.
>> Yes. I was just wondering, is this
actually Google Corporation that you
guys are contracting with?
>> Mr. Nelson, is Ring Central Google?
Tyler Nelson, uh, city IT, Mr. Mayor,
through you, um, Ring Central is not
affiliated with Google. Thank you. Did
that answer your question, Mr. Miller?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Anybody else in the audience?
All right. How about from the governing
body on the amendment? Anyone hearing?
None. All those in favor, please signify
by saying I.
>> I.
>> I. Those opposed. We're back on the main
motion. And I would like to note that we
have 58 cents. Makes me think of Mr.
Royal. Thank you. Any comments for
members of the governing body? Hearing
none. All those in favor, please signify
by saying I.
>> I.
>> Those opposed.
>> Uh, the agreement is approved as
amended.
>> Next item is number 24A on page five,
voucher report.
>> Is there anybody in the governing body
or in the audience that would like to
speak to the vouchers this evening?
Next item, please.
>> 24B. Announcement that due to the Martin
Luther King Jr. holiday on Monday,
January 19th, 2026, the regularly
scheduled city council committee
meetings will instead be held in city
council chambers, 21101 O'Neal Avenue,
Cheyenne, Wyoming, and via electronic
conference meeting as follows. Public
services committee will meet Tuesday,
January 20th, 2026 at noon. And finance
committee will meet Wednesday, January
21st, 2026 at noon. announcement of a
special meeting to be held January 23rd,
2026 at 12 o'clock PM in city council
chambers 21101 O'Neal Avenue, Shyan,
Wyoming, and via electronic conference
meeting to consider the transfer of
ownership of retail liquor license
application filed with the city clerk's
office for Westby Edge LLC doing
business as West Edge Brewing, 714 West
20th Street, Cheyenne, Wyoming. License
currently held by Scooter Scoreboard,
Inc. announcement that a committee of
the whole meeting will be will be held
Wednesday January 14th 2026 at 6:00 p.m.
in city council chambers 21101 O'Neal
Avenue Cheyenne Wyoming and via
electronic conference meeting other
business
>> all right we'll go out to the audience
is there anybody in the audience this
evening would like to speak to the
governing body under other business
all right hearing none how about from
the governing body Dr. Aldridge.
>> Mayor Collins through you. I would just
like to again remind everyone about
council and coffee in W 3 on January
17th this Saturday at Dosbog on the east
side of town from 9 to 11. Um and kudos
to my W one um colleagues who held a
very successful council and coffee for
their first one. Um welcome to the
council and coffee club. Um, we also
wanted to remind everyone that there is
a chili cookoff that the city council
will be participating in this Friday
night that will be held at the Archer
um, event center from 5:00 to 8:00 p.m.
that will benefit the Boys and Girls
Club. So, we encourage everyone to come
out and vote for uh, Councilman Esabel's
Green Chili and Councilman
>> award-winning green chili. We he'll
never let us forget that. And Councilman
Lebornne's red chili.
>> You make red chili?
Oh,
>> ladies and gentlemen, I have witnessed
and eaten both. They're delicious. Very,
very good.
>> Mr. Moody, did you have something?
>> Uh, yes, sir. Uh, thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Through you, just a reminder to the
public, we do have a we do have a uh on
this Wednesday, Council the whole for
six pennies. So, please come to make
your public comments. Great. You know,
public comments there. Please like to
have a lot of people give their input. I
will not be able to make council and
coffee on Saturday. I have to meet with
a constituent another issue and also too
just to pray for the protesters in Iran
and because of the uh hopefully they'll
end that theocratic regime. Thank you,
Mr. Mayor.
>> Mr. Wolf, did you have comments, sir?
>> I'm sorry.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Well, if we have no other
comments, um Mr. Crave,
>> Mr. Mr. Mayor, pursuant to Wyoming
static
>> microphone.
>> Mr. Mayor, pursuant to Wyoming statute
section 164405A7,
I move that the governing body meet in
executive session to consider or receive
any information classified as
confidential by law.
>> Is there a second?
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Mr. Leborn.
All those in favor of going into
executive session, please signify by
saying I. I
>> those opposed.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, u we're going to
go into executive session. When we come
out, we're just going to adjourn the
meeting. There'll be no other business
of the governing body. We wish you well
and thank you all for coming this
evening. It was entertaining. We loved
having everyone here.